nikebiz.com 2011-11-02

# What is Nike's Privacy Policy?

Please also visit our [Terms of Use](http://swoosh.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/16379) section that explains other terms governing the use of our Website.

Date of Last Revision: June 23, 2009

The following online privacy policy describes the information we collect and how we use it. By accessing or using this Website, you consent to our Privacy Policy. **You understand that regardless of which option you select in your privacy settings, NIKE does not guarantee any confidentiality or privacy with respect to any of your personal information or User Generated Content.** NIKE may modify this Privacy Policy at any time without notice, effective upon its posting to the Website. Your continued use of the Website constitutes your acceptance to this Privacy Policy and any updates. You agree to review this Privacy Policy regularly so that you understand our current Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and is subject to, the [Terms of Use](http://swoosh.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/16379). Any capitalized terms not defined in this policy have the meaning set forth in the [Terms of Use](http://swoosh.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/16379).

For questions or concerns, please contact us at:  
NIKE  
Attn: Consumer Services/Privacy  
One Bowerman Drive  
Beaverton, OR 9700  
1-800-806-643

 **Collecting Information**

When you visit NIKE's Website you provide us with personal information you knowingly disclose to us and Website interaction information collected by us. We request information from you (which may include name, age, address, telephone number, email address, city location, zip code, gender and when necessary, credit card information) when you register for the Website, make purchases, request a catalog, request to receive communications, or participate in a promotion or other Website feature.

In order to better understand your preferences and better serve you, we may combine information you give us online with other information from NIKE sources, transactions and communications. This may include data from the Website, NIKE stores, direct mail, events, or online marketing.  We may also combine that information with data that is publicly available and data that we receive from other reputable sources. We collect information about gift recipients to fulfill the gift purchase, respond to customer service inquiries and for analysis purposes only.

Like many websites, we gather information about how visitors use our Website. For more information, see the "Cookies and Pixel Tags" section below.

If you choose to use our invitation tools to invite friends to our Website, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your friends' email addresses, your email address, your Facebook account or other contact lists (e.g., Gmail, Twitter, Hotmail, and Yahoo). We will then invite your friends in your name to join the Website. NIKE stores certain information to send invitations and reminders and to track the success of our referral program.

 **Using Information**

We may use the information we collect to: 

  * Operate, provide, improve and maintain the Website
  * Send you administrative messages and information about NIKE in which we believe you may be interested
  * Customize and/or personalize your communications and shopping experience
  * Better respond to your customer service inquiries
  * Communicate with you about your purchase, account information or customer service needs
  * Communicate with you about our products and events, and for other promotional purposes
  * Improve our business
  * Administer contests, promotions, surveys or other Website features

If you have purchased a product from NIKE and have not previously registered on the Website as of April 19th, 2004, we will automatically add you to our direct mail (including catalog) list.

**Sharing Information for NIKE Business**

For the purpose of operating our business, we may transfer information between NIKE and our preferred service providers who use that information only to conduct NIKE business.  For example, they may handle NIKE's credit card processing, shipping, data management, email distribution, market research, information analysis, and promotions management.  We may also share your information to administer a Website feature (e.g. music download or race registration) and in that case will notify you before you give your information.  We provide our preferred service providers with the information they need to perform their services and work with them to protect your information.

We may provide your information to NIKE, Inc. wholly-owned companies and affiliates, which may be outside the U.S.  

We may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, when required by law, to enforce our Website policies, or to protect our or others' rights, property or safety. We may share information to prevent illegal uses of the Website or violations of the Terms of Use, or defend ourselves against third-party claims. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

 **Sharing Information with the Website Community**

By becoming a member of the Website, you agree to share a basic amount of information with the rest of the community, including your username, city location, profile picture and certain other basic information.  In order to participate in all of the additional Website features and community and sharing activities, you will have to change your privacy setting to share more information, including all your User Generated Content, your profile page and all your activity on the Website.

You may change your profile information and privacy settings or deactivate your account by logging into your account and accessing "Account Settings."  NIKE is not responsible for the actions of other users or the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on the Website. You post User Generated Content at your own risk. Therefore, please be mindful of what you post, because it may become publicly available on the Website or otherwise. Even after account deactivation, copies of your User Generated Content previously posted may still be viewable in activity fees, in other areas on the Website, on social platforms, in cached and archived pages or if other users have stored your User Generated Content. After account deactivation, NIKE may keep information and content in our backup files and archives.

Any published activity feed about you on the Website will be made available to other Website users. Your Website activity will also be made available to social platforms, such as Facebook and Twitter, if you choose to select that option. Please read the privacy policies of those social platforms, because your NIKE Website activity published on those platforms will no longer be governed by NIKE's Privacy Policy.

 **Protecting Your Information**

We use a variety of security measures, including encryption and authentication tools to maintain the safety of your personal information. When you place orders or access your personal information, we offer the use of a secure server. All credit card information you supply is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our databases to be accessed only as stated above. Regardless of these efforts, NIKE cannot guarantee 100% the security or confidentiality of the information you provide to us. We do not assume any liability to third parties whose information you include on the Website, or which you post in any User Generated Content. To help maintain the security of your NIKE account, please keep your password secure.

**Cookies and Pixel Tags**

NIKE receives and records information from your browser when you use the Website and may use a variety of methods, such as cookies and pixel tags to collect this information. A cookie is a small removable data file that is stored by your web browser on you computer. Cookies allow you to place an order on our Website and allow us to enhance and personalize your online experience.

For example, we use cookies to:

  * Remember the items in your shopping cart
  * Recognize you when you return to our Website
  * Store your username or login email (but not your password) to make it easer to login
  * Confirm that users are logged in
  * Enable you to use Express Checkout
  * Analyze visitor behavior

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent or you can choose to turn off all cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your Website experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly. However, you can still place product orders over the telephone by contacting our customer service number at 1-800-806-643.

We use pixel tags – tiny graphic images – to help us analyze your online behavior. Pixel tags also allow us to send you email in a format you can read and let us know when you have opened an email message from us. We may use pixel tags to collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken in connection with our Website. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, username, system type, whether you have enabling software to access certain Website features, access times and referring website addresses. Websites visited before visiting the NIKE Website might place personal information within the URL of your browser during a visit to that website. NIKE may unintentionally collect that information as part of the referring website information we collect.

We also work with other companies who use tracking technologies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These companies may collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our Website and your interaction with our communications, including advertising. If you would like to opt-out of 3rd party companies collecting non-personally identifiable information during your visits, please [click here](http://www.atlassolutions.com/optout.aspx).

 **Unsubscribing, Removing or Modifying Your Information**

Even if you remove your User Generated Content or terminate your NIKE account, copies of your User Generated Content may still be viewable in areas displayed outside your profile, in activity feeds, in other areas on the Website, on social platforms, in cached and archived pages or if other users have stored your User Generated Content.

We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to receive information from NIKE or would like to update or change your personal information or preferences, follow the instructions below. However, NIKE may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the Website or by email.

**Registration Information, Email and Other Subscriptions**

To modify or delete the information you have provided during registration, please login and update your profile. To unsubscribe from an email, please follow the instructions in any email you receive. Be sure to include your first and last name and account email address in the “message” box.

**Mobile Messaging**

To unsubscribe from SMS, MMS or other mobile messaging, please follow the instructions in the messages you receive.

**Direct Mail (Includes Catalogs)**

If you would like your name and address removed from NIKE's direct mailing list or if you would like to update your mailing information, you can phone us at 1-800-806-6453 (4:00am - 11:00pm Pacific Time, 7 days a week). Be sure to include your first and last name and mailing address in the “message” box.

**Communications in Progress/Sales and Service Information**

Please note, if you have unsubscribed from any NIKE communications, due to production schedules, you may receive communications already in production. Also, if you request your registration information be deleted or if you unsubscribe from communications, we may maintain information about sales transactions or service inquiries for future service and record keeping purposes.

**Children's Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under 13.

**International Users**

This website is operated, in whole or in part, from the United States. By using this Website, regardless of where you live in the world, you consent to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States, and allow NIKE to use and collect your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**Links**

NIKE may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible or liable for the privacy practices of other websites. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by NIKE.

**Terms of Use**

Your use of the Website, and any disputes arising from it, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our [Terms of Use](http://swoosh.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/16379). Please visit our [Terms of Use](http://swoosh.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/16379) section that explains other terms governing the use of our Website.
